usejournal.com 2019-04-17

# Journal

_Last Updated: 10/17/2018_

Protecting your privacy is really important to us. With this in mind, we're providing this Privacy Policy to explain our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information that we receive through our Services. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third-party websites, services or applications, even if they are accessible through our Services. Also, please note that, unless we define a term in this Privacy Policy, all capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Service. So, please make sure that you have read and understand our Terms of Service.

### Revisions to this Privacy Policy

Any information that is collected via our Services is covered by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we'll notify you of those changes by posting them on the Services or by sending you an email or other notification, and we'll update the "Last Updated Date" above to indicate when those changes will become effective.

### Collection and Use of Information

 **Information Collected or Received from You**

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Services, to administer your use of the Services (including your Account, if you are an Account holder), and to enable you to enjoy and easily navigate our Services.

 **Your Account Information.** If you create an Account, we'll collect certain information that can be used to identify you, such as your name and email address, (" **PII** "). We may collect this information directly from you, or, if you create an Account using your login credentials from one of your SNS Accounts, we'll be able to access and collect your name and email address and other PII that your privacy settings on the SNS Account permit us to access. If you create an Account through the Site or one of your SNS Accounts, we may also collect your gender, date of birth and other information that is not considered PII because it cannot be used by itself to identify you.

 **Third-Party Account Information.** We may obtain information about you from other sources, including through third-party services and organizations, to supplement information provided by you. If you have an Account, in order to provide the Services to you, we'll access, collect and, in some instances, store some or all of Your Content from Third-Party Accounts that you link to your Account.

You may also have the option, after linking your Account to Third-Party Accounts, to choose which information from Your Content is accessed, collected, and stored on the Services. If you choose this option, we will only have access to, collect, and store the information specifically selected by you. You may also have the option to avoid integrating your Account to any Third-Party Account, and instead may add Your Content manually to the Services.

Examples of Third-Party Accounts that may be linked to your Account include Google's Gmail, Calendar, and Drive accounts. Examples of information that we may access, collect, and/or store from your Third-Party Accounts include e-mail communications, information about the interaction you have via email with individuals with whom you communicate, calendar event information, contact information from your Gmail address books and other data from your Third-Party Accounts. We may also combine, enhance or aggregate information from your Third-Party Accounts with publicly-available information, including information about you as permitted by applicable law.

 **Information Collected Using Cookies and other Web Technologies.** Like many website owners and operators, we use automated data collection tools such as Cookies and Web Beacons to collect certain information. We also collect information through authorized APIs and registration forms.

" **Cookies** " are small text files that are placed on your device by a Web server when you access our Services. We may use both session Cookies and persistent Cookies to identify that you've logged in to the Services and to tell us how and when you interact with our Services. We may also use Cookies to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on our Services and to customize and improve our Services. Unlike persistent Cookies, session Cookies are deleted when you log off from the Services and close your browser. Although most browsers automatically accept Cookies, you can change your browser options to stop automatically accepting Cookies or to prompt you before accepting Cookies. Please note, however, that if you don't accept Cookies, you may not be able to access all portions or features of the Services. Some third-party services providers that we engage (including third-party advertisers) may also place their own Cookies on your device. Note that this Privacy Policy covers only our use of Cookies and does not include use of Cookies by such third parties.

" **Web Beacons** " (also known as Web bugs, pixel tags or clear GIFs) are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that may be included on our Services for several purposes, including to deliver or communicate with Cookies, to track and measure the performance of our Services, to monitor how many visitors view our Services, and to monitor the effectiveness of our advertising. Unlike Cookies, which are stored on the user's device, Web Beacons are typically embedded invisibly on web pages. We may also include web beacons in e-mails to understand whether messages have been opened, acted on, or forwarded.

 **Information from Third Party Advertising Parties.** We may also collect information from third party advertising parties to improve the functionality of our Services or for marketing purposes. These third-party advertising parties may collect your PII to provide content that is more relevant to you. For more information about our use of third-party advertising parties, please contact us as set forth below.

 **Information Related to Use of the Services.** Our servers automatically record certain information about how a person uses our Services (we refer to this information as " **Log Data** "), including both Account holders and non-Account holders (either, a " **User** "). Log Data may include information such as a User's Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, operating system, the web page that a User was visiting before accessing our Services, the pages or features of our Services to which a User browsed and the time spent on those pages or features, search terms, the links on our Services that a User clicked on and other statistics. We use Log Data to administer the Services and we analyze (and may engage third parties to analyze) Log Data to improve, customize and enhance our Services by expanding their features and functionality and tailoring them to our Users' needs and preferences. We may also use a person's IP address to generate aggregate, non-identifying information about how our Services are used.

 **Information Sent by Your Mobile Device.** We may collect certain information that your mobile device sends when you use our Services, like a device identifier, user settings and the operating system of your device, as well as information about your use of our Services, in order to provide services on your mobile device.

 **Location Information.** When you use our App, we may collect and store information about your location by converting your IP address into a rough geo-location or by accessing your mobile device's GPS coordinates or coarse location if you enable location services on your device. We may use location information to improve and personalize our Services for you.

 **Information Collected for Marketing Purposes.** We may collect certain information, such as your first name and email addresses, for marketing purposes including sending newsletters and promotional emails. For those who sign up for our waitlist to receive waitlist and product-related communications, we may collect other information such as company name, types of other services you use at work, and how you intend to use our product.

### Information that We Share with Third Parties

We will not share any PII that we have collected from or regarding you except as described below:

 **Information Shared with Our Services Providers.** We may engage third-party services providers to work with us to administer and provide the Services. These third-party services providers, such as website hosting service providers and customer communication platforms (e.g. Intercom), have access to your PII only for the purpose of performing services on our behalf.

 **Information Shared with Third Parties.** We may share aggregated information and non-identifying information with third parties for industry research and analysis, demographic profiling and other similar purposes. We collect this information from both users with Accounts and visitors to our Site. We utilize Google Analytics, a service provided by Google, Inc., that we use to gather information about how visitors engage with our Services. For more information about Google Analytics, please visit www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.

 **Information Disclosed in Connection with Business Transactions.** Information that we collect from our users, including PII, is considered to be a business asset. Thus, if we are acquired by a third party as a result of a transaction such as a merger, acquisition or asset sale or if our assets are acquired by a third party in the event we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, some or all of our assets, including your PII, may be disclosed or transferred to a third party acquirer in connection with the transaction. **This information, including your PII, will continue to be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy in the event of a transaction.**

 **Information Disclosed for Our Protection and the Protection of Others.** We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials or private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate: (i) to respond to claims, legal process (including subpoenas); (ii) to protect our property, rights and safety and the property, rights and safety of a third party or the public in general; and (iii) to stop any activity that we consider illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

### Your Choices

We offer you choices regarding the collection, use and sharing of your PII and we'll respect the choices you make. Please note that if you decide not to provide us with the PII that we request, you may not be able to access all of the features of the Services.

 **Opt-Out.** We may periodically send you free newsletters and e-mails that directly promote our Services. When you receive such promotional communications from us, you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" (either through your Account or by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive). We do need to send you certain communications regarding the Services and you will not be able to opt out of those communications -- e.g., communications regarding updates to our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy or information about billing.

 **Modifying Your Information.** You can access and modify the PII associated with your Account via the functionality of the Services. We'll take steps to delete your information as soon we can, but some information may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law.

 **Right to Object to Processing.** You have the right to object to or opt out of certain uses of your PII. Where you have consented to the processing of your PII, you may withdraw that consent at any time and prevent further processing by contacting us as described below. Even if you opt out, we may still collect and use non-PII regarding your activities on our Site, Services and/or information from the advertisements on third party websites for other legal purposes as described above.

 **Rights of Access, Rectification, Erasure, and Restriction.** In accordance with applicable law, you may have the right to: (i) request confirmation of whether we are processing your PII; (ii) obtain access to or a copy of your PII (iii) receive an electronic copy of PII that you have provided to us, or ask us to send that information to another company (the "right of data portability"); (iv) restrict our uses of your PII; (v) seek correction or amendment of inaccurate, untrue, incomplete, or improperly processed PII; and (vi) request erasure of PII held about you by Journal, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at as set forth below.

We will process such requests in accordance with applicable laws. To protect your privacy, Journal will take steps to verify your identity before fulfilling your request.

 **Responding to Do Not Track Signals**

Our Site does not have the capability to respond to "Do Not Track" signals received from various web browsers.

 **The Security of Your Information**

We take reasonable administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect the information that we collect from or about you (including your PII) from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of any information.

 **Links to Other Sites**

Our Services may contain links to websites and services that are owned or operated by third parties (each, a " **Third-party Service** "). Any information that you provide on or to a Third-party Service or that is collected by a Third-party Service is provided directly to the owner or operator of the Third-party Service and is subject to the owner's or operator's privacy policy. We're not responsible for the content, privacy or security practices and policies of any Third-party Service. To protect your information we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of all Third-party Services that you access.

 **International Transfer**

Your PII may be transferred to, processed, and stored anywhere in the world, including but not limited to, the European Union, the United States or other countries where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you're located outside the United States and choose to provide your PII to us, we may transfer your PII to the United States and process it there.

 **Supervisory Authority** If you are located in the European Economic Area, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you believe our processing of your PII violates applicable law.

 **Our Policy Toward Children**

Our Services are not directed to children under 13 and we do not knowingly collect PII from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected PII of a child under 13 we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

 **Data Retention**

We retain the PII we received as described in this Privacy Policy for as long as you use our Services or as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected, provide our Services, resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements, and comply with applicable laws.

 **Your California Privacy Rights**

California residents may request and obtain from us, once a year, free of charge, a list of third parties, if any, to which we disclosed their PII for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year and the categories of PII shared with those third parties. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain that information, please submit your request by sending us an email at hello@usejournal.com with "California Privacy Rights" in the subject line or by writing to us at 222 Columbus Avenue, San Francisco, California 94133.

 **Questions?**

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at hello@usejournal.com or 222 Columbus Ave #300, San Francisco, CA 94133.
